Yuqian Zhou

Email | Homopage | Google Scholar | Github | Linkedin

RESEARCH INTEREST

My current research focuses on image restoration, generation and editing. I am also interested in multiview computer vision and structure analysis from image collections. I am actively conducting research on computer vision algorithm with limited-quality inputs, and doing inter-disciplinary research like medical image analysis.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (UIUC),

Aug. 2017 - Present

Image Formation and Processing Group (IFP), Beckman Institute

Advisor: Prof. Thomas Huang (1936-2020), Prof. Mark Hasegawa-Johnson Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) ABD in Electrical and Computer Engineering Cumulative GPA: 4.0/4.0

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST),

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2017

Neuromorphic Interactive System Lab, ECE Advisor: Prof. Bertram Shi

Master of Philosophy (M.Phil.) in Electronics and Computer Engineering

Cumulative GPA: 4.04/4.3

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST),

Aug. 2013 - Aug. 2015

Winner of the 2015 HKUST Academic Achievement Medal

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.) in Computer Engineering

Cumulative GPA: 4.086/4.3, Ranking: 1/130

Sun Yat Sen University (SYSU), Guangzhou, China

Aug. 2011 - Aug. 2013

Undergraduate Student in Computer Science

Cumulative GPA: 3.8/4.0, Ranking: 1/20

Peking University, China

Jul. 2014 - Aug. 2014

Globex Engineering School Summer Exchange Program

Courses: Nanomedicine

PROFESSIONAL APPOINTMENTS

Research Assistant

Aug. 2017 - Present

- @ Image Formation and Processing (IFP) Group, UIUC, supervised by Mark Hasegawa-Johnson
- Image Processing and Restoration, Human-computer Interaction, Medical Imaging

Research Intern

May. 2020 - present

- @ Adobe Research & Adobe Photoshop with Sohrab Amirghodsi, Connelly Barnes, Eli Shechtman
- Improving Photoshop Content-Aware Fill and Multi-source Image Inpainting

Research Intern

May. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- @ Microsoft Applied Science Group & Microsoft Research with Tim Large
- Image Restoration for Under-display Camera

Research Intern

May. 2018 - Aug. 2018

@ Meqvii co. USA Research with Jue Wang

- Real-world Image Blind Denoising and Deformable Style Transfer

Research Assistant Aug. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- @ Jump Trading Research Lab with Ken Terao
- Single-stock and Multi-stock High-Frequency Trading Algorithm

Research Assistant Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2017

- @ Neruomorphic Interactive System Lab, HKUST, with Bertram Shi
- Affective Computing and Intelligent Robotics

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Publications:

- 1. Y. Zhou, C. Barnes, E. Shechtman, S. Amirghodsi, "TransFill: Reference-guided Image Inpainting by Merging Multiple Color and Spatial Transformations", *IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2021.
- 2. Y. Zhou, D. Ren, N. Emerton, S. Lim, T. Large, "Image restoration for under-display camera", IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021.
- 3. Y. Mei, Y. Fan, Y. Zhou." Image Super-Resolution with Non-Local Sparse Attention", *IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2021.
- 4. H. Yu, N. Xu, Z. Huang, Y. Zhou, H. Shi, "High-Resolution Deep Image Matting", The AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021.
- 5. Y. Mei, Y. Fan, Y. Zhou, L. Huang, T. Huang, H. Shi, "Image Super-Resolution with Cross-Scale Non-Local Attention and Exhaustive Self-Exemplars Mining", *IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2020.
- Y. Zhou, J. Jiao, H. Huang, Y. Wang, J. Wang, H. Shi, T. Huang, "When AWGN-based Denoiser Meets Real Noises", The AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020.
- K. Gu, Y. Zhou¹, T. Huang, "FLNet: Landmark Driven Fetching and Learning Network for Faithful Talking Facial Animation Synthesis", The AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020.
- 8. D. Deng, Z. Chen, Y. Zhou, B. Shi, "Integrating Micro- and Macro-motion for Video Emotion Recognition", The AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020.
- 9. Y. Fu, Y. Wei, G. Wang, Y. Zhou, H. Shi, T. Huang, "Self-similarity Grouping: A Simple Unsupervised Cross Domain Adaptation Approach for Person Re-identification", *IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2019. [Oral]
- 10. T. He, H. Huang, L. Yi, **Y. Zhou**, C. Wu, J. Wang, S. Soatto, "GeoNet: Deep Geodesic Networks for Point Cloud Analysis", *IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (CVPR), 2019. [Oral]
- 11. Y. Fu, Y. Wei, Y. Zhou, H. Shi, G. Huang, X. Wang, Z. Yao, T. Huang, "Horizontal Pyramid Matching for Person Re-identification", *The AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)*, 2019.
- 12. **Y. Zhou**, K. Gu, T. Huang, "Unsupervised Representation Adversarial Learning Network: from Reconstruction to Generation", *The International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)*, 2019. [Oral]

¹Corresponding Author

- 13. **Y. Zhou**, D. Liu, T. Huang, "Survey of Face Detection on Low-quality Images", *IEEE International Conference on Automatic Face & Gesture Recognition* (**FG**), 2018.
- 14. Y. Zhou, B. Shi, "Photorealistic Facial Expression Synthesis by the Conditional Difference Adversarial Autoencoder", The International Conference on Affective Computing and Intelligent Interaction (ACII), 2017.
- 15. **Y. Zhou**, J. Pi, B. Shi, "Pose-independent Facial Action Unit Intensity Regression Based on Multi-task Deep Transfer Learning", *IEEE International Conference on Automatic Face & Gesture Recognition (FG)*, 2017. [Winner of the FERA2017 Challenge] [Oral]
- 16. **Y. Zhou**, B. Shi, "Action Unit Selective Feature Maps in Deep Networks for Facial Expression Recognition", The International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), 2017. [Oral]

Journal Publications:

*Y. Zhou, *YW. Lin², F. Faghri, MJ. Shaw, RH. Campbell, "Analysis and Prediction of Unplanned Intensive Care Unit Readmission using Recurrent Neural Networks with Long Short-Term Memory", PLoS ONE, July, 2018

Other Publications:

- 1. **Y. Zhou**, H. Yu, H. Shi, "Study Group Learning: Improving Retinal Vessel Segmentation Trained with Noisy Labels, *Technical Report*
- 2. **Y. Zhou**, M. Kwan, K. Tolentino, N. Emerton, S. Lim, T. Large ... ,"UDC 2020 Challenge on Image Restoration of Under-Display Camera: Methods and Results", European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Workshop, 2020. (Challenge Report)
- 3. Y. Mei, Y. Fan, Y. Zhang, J. Yu, Y. Zhou, D. Liu, Y. Fu, T. Huang, H. Shi, "Pyramid Attention Networks for Image Restoration", Technical Report
- Y. Zhou, J. Jiao, H. Huang, J. Wang, T. Huang, "Adaptation Strategies for Applying AWGN-based Denoiser to Realistic Noise", The AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2019. (Student Abstract)
- J. Liu, CH. Wu, Y. Wang, Q. Xu, Y. Zhou, H. Huang, C. Wang, S. Cai, Y. Ding ... "Learning Raw Image Denoising with Bayer Pattern Unification and Bayer Preserving Augmentation", IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops, 2019. [Winner of NTIRE 2019 Raw Track]. (Challenge Report)
- 6. A. Abdelhamed, ..., Y. Zhou,..., "Ntire 2020 challenge on real image denoising: Dataset, methods and results", IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops, 2020. (Challenge Report)
- 7. A. Abdelhamed, ..., Y. Zhou,..., "Ntire 2019 challenge on real image denoising: Methods and results", IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops, 2019. (Challenge Report)

BOOKS

1. Y. Zhou, "Thirteen days travel to the U.S.", 2006, ISBN:9787270206070

PATENT

- 1. "Deep learning based Multi-homography Fused Multi-source Image Inpainting", US Patent filed, 2020 (Filed with Adobe Inc.)
- 2. "Image Restoration for Through-display Imaging", US Patent filed, 2019 (Filed with Microsoft)

²Equal Contributions

DATASET AND SOFTWARE

- 1. Codes associated with the publications are open-sourced at my Github page.
- 2. "Testing Dataset for Reference-based Image Inpainting", released, Adobe Research, 2021
- 3. "Under-Display Camera Dataset for T-OLED and P-OLED", released, Microsoft Applied Science Group, 2021
- 4. "Generalized Image Restoration Toolbox", in preparation, UIUC, 2019-present

AWARDS, HONORS AND SCHOLARSHIP

Research Awards:

• 5th Dlage of NTIDE2020 aDCD Image Denoising Challenge at CVDD 2020	Ann. 2020
• 5th Place of NTIRE2020 sRGB Image Denoising Challenge at CVPR 2020	Apr. 2020
• 3rd Place of Dunhuang e-Heritage Challenge at ICCV 2019	Aug. 2019
• 1st Place of NTIRE2019 Raw Image Denoising Challenge at CVPR 2019	Jun. 2019
• 3rd Price of the 15th 'Challenge Cup' of China	Nov. 2017
• 1st Place of 2017 Facial Expression Recognition Challenge (FERA2017)	Jun. 2017
• Best Oral Paper of ICBDA 2017	Mar. 2015
• Finalist of Three-Minute-Thesis(3MT) Challenge of HKUST	Dec. 2015
• 3rd Price at ACM Competition of SYSU	Mar. 2012

Grants and Fellowship:

• Thomas and Margaret Huang Award for Graduate Research	Apr. 2020
• Postgraduate Studentship of HKUST	Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2017
• First-class Scholarship Scheme for Continuing UG Students of HKUST	Aug. 2014
• HKTIIT Scholarship	Aug. 2014
• First-class Scholarship of SYSU	Aug. 2013
• Jerry Yan Scholarship	Aug. 2013
• Soong Ching Ling Scholarship	Aug. 2006

Earlier Recognition:

• 2015 Academic Achievement Medal of HKUST (top 0.1%)	Nov. 2015
• 2015 HKUST Outstanding Student (top 1%)	May 2015
• 2015 HKUST Academic Excellence Award (top 5%)	May 2015
• HKUST Dean's List (top 10%)	Sep. 2015
• HKUST Dean's List (top 10%)	Sep. 2014
• HKUST Dean's List (top 10%)	May 2014

Selected Media Coverage:

- Awared the Thomas and Margaret Huang Award for Graduate Research, "Beckman spring award, fellowship recipients announced", Beckman Institute, UIUC headlines, 2020.
- High Resolution Image Matting is highlighted and covered by The Heart of Machine, "It's not enough to cut out the fineness to the hair. Adobe's new method can process 6000×6000 high-resolution images", The Heart of Machine Headlines, (in Chinese), 2021.
- Our Under-Display Camera Project is covered by Sparrows News, "Microsoft's AI Repair Program will Solve Blurring Problem Of In-display Camera", 2020
- The Under-Display Camera Research is highlighted at Microsoft Applied Science Group Project Pages, "Camera In Display", Microsoft Headlines, 2020
- Won the Challenge of NTIRE 2019 on the Track of RAW Image Denoising, "CVPR 2019, How the Megvii Research Winning 6 Championships Builds Algorithmic Barriers", The Heart of Machine Headlines, (in Chinese), 2019. Also by Megvii Research Headlines.
- Won the Facial Expression Recognition Challenge, "ECE PG Students Won the Action Unit Intensity Estimation Sub-challenge in the Facial Expression Recognition and Analysis Challenge 2017", ECE headlines by HKUST, 2017

• The book written by me when I was 16-year-old was covered by local media, "Visiting the United States for 13 days, 16-year-old middle school student completed a 100,000-word book", 2006

PRESENTATIONS

Selected Invited Talks:

• "TransFill: Reference-guided Image Inpainting", Adobe Tech Summit, virtual	Apr. 2021
• "Overview of Image Inpainting", SHI Lab Meeting at University of Oregon, virtual	Mar. 2021
• "Affective Computing and its Applications on Online Learning", School of Information	ion Sciences
of UIUC, virtual	Mar. 2021
• "Affective Computing on Online Learning", IBM Research, virtual	Nov. 2020
• "Challenge on Under-Display Camera", ECCV RLQ-TOD Workshop, virtual	Aug. 2020
• "Multi-source Inpainting", Adobe Intern Talk, virtual	Aug. 2020
• "Introduction to Low-quality Vision", ICCV RLQ Workshop, Seoul, Korea	Oct. 2019
• "Domain-adaptive Person Re-ID", ICCV WIDER Workshop, Seoul, Korea	Oct. 2019
• "Domain-adaptive Person Re-ID", ICCV Oral, Seoul, Korea	Oct. 2019
• "Under-Display Camera", IFP Group Meeting, Urbana, IL	Sep. 2019
• "Under-Display Camera", Microsoft Intern Talk, Redmond, WA	Aug. 2019
• "Deep AU-Selective Feature Maps for Expression Recognition", 16-th Japan-China-	-Korea Join
Workshop on Neurobiology and Neuroinformatics (NBNI 2016), HK, China	Dec. 2016

MENTORING

- Jitesh Jain, Undergrad, IIT, Mar. 2021 present
- Michael Kwan, ECE Undergrad, UIUC, Sep. 2019 present (After: CMU ECE Master Program)
- Kyle Tolentino, ECE Undergrad, UIUC, Sep. 2019 present
- Yiqun Mei, ECE Undergrad, UIUC, Jan. 2020 present (After: JHU PhD Program)

TEACHING

- Invited Lecturer, UIUC ARTD 499: Special Topics in Design AI and Design (Fall 2021)
- Teaching Assistant, UIUC ECE 448: Artificial Intelligence (Fall 2019)

SERVICES

Main Program Organizer:

- ECCV Challenge on Under-Display Camera (UDC 2020), virtual, 2020
- ECCV Workshop on Real-World Recognition (RLQ-TOD 2020), virtual, 2020
- ICCV Workshop on Real-World Recognition (RLQ 2019), Seoul, Korea, 2019

Program Chair:

- IEEE International Conference on Big Data Analysis (ICBDA), Suzhou, China, 2019
- IEEE International Conference on Big Data Analysis (ICBDA), Shanghai, China, 2018
- IJCAI Affective Computing Workshop, virtual, 2020

Frequent Reviewer:

- Journal: TIP, Cybernetics, Computational Survey, Affective Computing, Visual Communication and Image Representation, etc.
- Conference: CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, NeruIPS, AAAI, ICLR, ICML, ACCV, WACV, MICCAI, etc.

Interviewer:

• HKUST Undergraduate Student Admission Interview after DSE

Volunteer:

• Animal shelter volunteer at Champaign, IL

 Student Ambassador of New Semester Series Events International Volunteer of Maldives Environment Protection and Education Volunteered at the Anniversary of China-HK Scholar Association Tutor in Hong Kong Tutor Association HKUST Exchange Student Partner Blood Donation at Harbin, China 	2015-2016 2012-2013 2017 2015-2017 2013-2017 2013
Miscellaneous:	
 Chairman of the Maxcell Resourse Sharing Association at SYSU Group Leader of the Academic Department of SYSU Student Union Chairman of the Student Union of Harbin No.3 Senior High Delegate of Estonia at WHO of Harvard Model United Nations Conference Academic Advisor of the Heilongjiang Model United Nations Conference China-Denmark Culture Exchange Program Junior Journalist of China-US Culture Exchange Program 	2012-2013 2011-2012 2009-2010 Dec. 2010 Aug. 2010 Dec. 2009 Dec. 2006